Nguyen Thanh Dat

209 Le Hong Phong, D5, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

(84) 90 669 5527 - dat.nguyenthanhit@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/datnguyenthanh/

About Me

An engineer focuses mainly on mobile development - With 4 years of experience and passion for mobile development - Hardworking and forward thinking - A willing-to-learn attitude and a confident communicator - Both a team player and independently self-working

Working Experience

Software Engineer at Grab (March 2017 - Present)

Grab is more than just the leading ride-hailing app in Southeast Asia. We use data and technology to improve everything from transportation to payments and logistics across a region of more than 620 million people. Working with governments, drivers, passengers, and charities, we aim to unlock the true potential of the region by solving problems that hinder progress.

Grab began as a taxi-hailing app in 2012, but has extended its product platform to include private car services (GrabCar & GrabShare), motorcycle taxis (GrabBike), social carpooling (GrabHitch) and last mile delivery (GrabExpress). We are focused on pioneering new commuting alternatives for drivers and passengers with an emphasis on speed, safety, and reliability. Currently we offer services in Singapore, Indonesia, Philippines, Malaysia, Thailand and Vietnam; however, we also have R&D offices in Bangalore, Beijing, & Seattle."

Mobile Engineer as a freelancer (October 2013 - Present)

Working as a mobile engineer freelancer to build and maintain various mobile applications using either native Android or cross-platform framework React Native.

Senior Mobile Developer at Silicon Straits Saigon (May 2016 - February 2017)

Actively developing and maintaining a ride-hailing passenger app for one of the biggest taxi company in South East Asia using RxJava2, Dagger2, MVP and MVVM.

Software Developer at TRG International (February 2013 - April 2016)

- Take an active role in the full development circle including planning, requirement gathering, design, development, testing as well as maintaining.
- Responsible for both frontend and backend development.
- Working with wide range of development languages and CMS such as PHP, VBA, VB.NET, Java, C#,
 Magento
- Maintain MySQL, SQLite and Oracle database

Android Development:

- Focus on Android development using Android Studio as the main IDE.
- Created a variety of Android applications from pre-defined technical specifications with involving in every project phrase from concept planning to app deployment both for internal and external.
- Build and integrate SOAP and Restful Services as the middle communicator between application and database.
- Test applications on multiple devices running different versions of Android.
- Integrate third party API such as Facebook and Google Maps
- Experience with Android native SMS system in order to replicate SMS app with custom features
- Application /client pool: NMNG app (New Music and Gigs), Cham Card (AmCham Vietnam), TRG Internal (TRG), Smart SMS

Projects

GreatPeople (React Native)

With **GreatPeople** you can view jobs from your employer, send referrals and create a shortlist of great people that you think should be working with you.

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.recruitapp

My Blue Bird Taxi (Native Android)

My Blue Bird is one of the biggest taxi brand in South East Asia located in Indonesia with more than 30,000 taxis. In order to compete with Uber and Grab, they need to advanced high-tech solution for booking and dispatching taxi instead of old-fashioned way. - Build and maintain a ride-hailing passenger app using native Android. - Working on complex architecture from backend to client. - Familiar with RxJava2, Dagger 2, MVP, and MVVM - Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.seatech.bluebird

Cognito CRM (React Native)

Cognito is a very fresh CRM system specified for Vietnam local market which helps to boost the marketing

and sales process much faster than any other mediums by automation. Recently, the need of mobile app arises in order to assist sales to follow and keep track of their customers. - User React Native combined with Redux which helps to manage states of different components. - Besides, a more scalable and easy-to-maintain structure is also applied (redux, redux-saga, apisauce and reduxsauce) to ease the effort of working as team of 3-4 developers.

New Music and GIGs (React Native)

New Music and GIGs (NMNG) introduces a new way to promote new artists and bands in UK and bring their music close to the online community. Besides the website, they also need to approach mobile users due to recently fact, people love to listen to music on their smart phones. - Use React Native (framework introduced by Facebook) to build cross-platform mobile app which run smoothly on both Android and iOS devices. - Integrate with other third party services such as Facebook, Google and Songkick. - Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.nmng - App Store: https://itunes.apple.com/vn/app/newmusic-and-gigs/id1102778296?mt=8

Education

Coder School iOS Bootcamp (Swift) - October to December 2015

Coderschool.vn (http://www.coderschool.vn)

Bachelor of Business (Business Information Systems) - 2011 to 2014

RMIT University Vietnam (Saigon South Campus)

High school for Gifted - 2007 to 2010

High school, Social Sciences

Skils

- Native Android Development (kotlin, rxJava, dagger, MVP)
- React Native (redux, typescript, redux-saga)
- Swift
- Git
- SQL
- Data Structure